## Siddaharth Suman

Software Engineer III

## **Objectives**

Looking for a continuous learning environment and professional growth in an organization where my skills are adequately utilized.

I wish to contribute the skills that I have learned over the years for the betterment of the organization.

#### **About Me**

I am a Software Engineer III with a total experience of 5 years working with FactSet Systems India Pvt Ltd.

I am a self-motivated and adaptable kind of individual who yearns to get his hands on the latest trends in technology.

I am a quick learner and a team player who is neither afraid to take lead nor afraid to ask for help in case I get stuck anywhere.

I possess good communication, interpersonal, and leadership skills and can effectively deal with teammates and clients. I am always willing to help others in need and motivate them and boost their morale.

I like to work as a team and look forward to working with teams where I can contribute with my expertise as well as learn from.

## **Experience**

## Dec 2018 -Present

## Software Engineer III

FactSet Systems India Pvt. Ltd.

- · Worked on endpoint development for simple access to company's dataset
- Worked on the company's financial data tool used by banks and financial institutions

### Dec 2015 - Dec 2018

#### Senior System Engineer

Infosys Ltd.

- · Worked on web applications and mobile applications
- · Worked on development of automated tools and perform testing of web applications
- Provided middleware support

# Aug 2015 - Oct 2015

#### **Assistant Professor**

Institute of Forensic Science

- · Worked as a faculty for the institute
- · Taught the subject of Cyber Forensics and Offenses

## May 2014 - Oct 2014

## Freelancer

Palmate Solutions

Worked as a Backend Web Developer

#### Jan 2014 - Mar 2014

## Intern

TechMeet

• Worked as an Android Application Developer

## Jun 2013 - Oct 2013

#### Intern

Opine Solutions

· Worked as an Android Application Developer

## **Projects**

## Endpoint development

Technologies: Javascript, NodeJS

Team Size: 2

- · Endpoint development for ease of use by developers to request company's dataset and query them
- Users can alternatively use UI to perform queries and get results as well
- · Worked on two such endpoints and received appreciation by the team
- Received award for the project

# Financial data tool

Technologies: Java, Php, WixToolset, Msi

Team Size: 5

- Standalone product used by banks and financial institutions
- · Worked as acting lead on the project and ensured timely delivery of tasks and resolution of issues
- Worked on creation of custom Java packages and Msi packages
- · Worked on migration from Teamcity to Jenkins and performing build automations and deployments
- · Received award for the project

## Partner Assessment Portal

**Technologies:** Angular 5, Bulma, CSS, HTML, Javascript, Typescript **Team Size:** 8

- Portal for partners of the firm to be assessed on their performance and get recommendation for salary changes
- Superiors can see a partner's summary, history and other information
- Superiors can provide a salary recommendation for partners based on their assessment
- · Worked directly with client

### Personal Info

#### Phone

+91 9920760964

#### E-mail

siddaharthsuman@gmail.com

#### Date of birth

December 18, 1993

#### **Marital Status**

Unmarried

#### Github

github.com/SiddaharthSuman

# Frameworks

- Angular
- Vue.js
- Bulma
- Bootstrap
- Java Swing
- JavaFX

## Backend Technologies/ Frameworks

- Node.js
- Php
- Servlets

## **Mobile Technologies**

Android

# Markup and Scripting Languages

- HTML
- JavaScript
- CSS
- jQuery
- Php

## **Programming Languages**

- Java
- Typescript
- C++
- Python

# Testing Frameworks and Tools

- Selenium
- Katalon StudioHP UFT
- Coded UI

## Databases

- MySQL
- MSSQL
- MongoDB

## Version Control

• Git

Bitbucket

## **Tools**

- TeamCity
- HP Service Manager 9
- Lifecycle Management
- Visual Studio
- · IBM Websphere

· HP Application

## **IDEs and Editors**

- Eclipse
- Visual Studio
- Atom
   Cublines Tout
- Code

Profile and Rewards Web Application **Technologies:** Angular 4, Bootstrap, CSS, HTML, jQuery, Javascript, Typescript **Team Size:** 12

- Employee centric dashboard with various reports and details of the employee
- · Employees can generate their compensation, health and time off related reports
- Received appreciation from teammates and onsite team as well for good performance

Geofence and Custom Plugin for Workspace Reservation

Technologies: Android, Ionic, Cordova

Team Size: 10

- · Application for employees for reserving workspaces in their office
- · Employees can reserve workspaces on a temporary or regular basis as well
- Employees can schedule reservation for future dates and can automatically get a reservation as soon as entering the work area

MobileIron Downloads Report Tool **Technologies:** Selenium, JavaFX, Apache POI, MobileIron, Microsoft Excel, PhantomJS **Team Size:** 1

- Automation tool that generates reports for 80+ production applications
- Enables employees to work on other tasks and not be blocked on creating report manually
- Manual report generation blocks an employee for 1 hour and is prone to human errors
- · The tool takes under 5 minutes to generate the report and is accurate every time
- Received appreciation from offshore as well as onshore team for simplicity and time saving

PwC Application Details Portal **Technologies:** Angular 4, Php, Servlets, Google Drive, Soap **Team Size:** 1

- Portal for details of applications supported by the support team
- Gives access to internal details of 26+ applications across many territories
- Facility to manage applications list, ping application's soap services and manage relevant documents using integrated Google Drive support
- Performs automatic healthcheck for all the applications
- Received appreciation from team

Infosys Buy/Sell App for Android Technologies: Android, Php, MySQL

Team Size: 5

- · App for a buy/sell platform
- · Users can post items for selling and can also see other posts
- Users can show interest in an item for sale and contact the seller

## **Education**

Sep 2011 - May 2015

#### Atharva College of Engineering, Mumbai University, BE in Computer Engineering, 2015

- Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" for EXTC faculties
- Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" for CMPN and INFT faculties
- Conducted Training and Placement Session on "C++" for final year students
- Held the posts of Assistant Technical Head and Technical Head for Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Java Primer" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Backend Web Development" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Speaker for workshop on "Android Application Development" organised by Computer Society of India, Atharva
- Organised Google Dev Fest for Google Developer's Group

till Mar 2011

Kendriya Vidyalaya INS Hamla, Mumbai

## **Publications**

Feb 2015

Supercharging web applications with Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-1 Feb 2015)

Jun 2015

Information system using Dart and MongoDB (IJCET Vol 5-3 June 2015)

### **Operating Systems**

- Windows
- Mac OS
- Linux

## Languages

- · English
- Hindi
- Marathi